<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Deep Learning on Yida Wang&#39;s personal website</title>
    <link>https://wangyida.github.io/tags/deep-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Deep Learning on Yida Wang&#39;s personal website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016 Yida Wang</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/deep-learning/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Learning</title>
      <link>https://wangyida.github.io/project/deep-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wangyida.github.io/project/deep-learning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Deep learning (also known as deep structured learning or hierarchical learning) is part of a broader family of machine learning methods based on learning data representations, as opposed to task-specific algorithms. Learning can be supervised, partially supervised or unsupervised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some representations are loosely based on interpretation of information processing and communication patterns in a biological nervous system, such as neural coding that attempts to define a relationship between various stimuli and associated neuronal responses in the brain. Research attempts to create efficient systems to learn these representations from large-scale, unlabeled data sets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deep learning architectures such as deep neural networks, deep belief networks and recurrent neural networks have been applied to fields including computer vision, speech recognition, natural language processing, audio recognition, social network filtering, machine translation and bioinformatics where they produced results comparable to and in some cases superior[6] to human experts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
