<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Yida Wang</title>
    <link>https://wangyida.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Yida Wang</description>
    <image>
      <title>Yida Wang</title>
      <url>http://campar.in.tum.de/twiki/pub/Main/YidaWang/YidaWang_CAMP.png</url>
      <link>http://campar.in.tum.de/twiki/pub/Main/YidaWang/YidaWang_CAMP.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.147.8</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 10:15:01 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://wangyida.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>HiNeuS - High-fidelity Neural Surface Mitigating Low-texture and Reflective Ambiguity</title>
      <link>https://wangyida.github.io/posts/hineus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 10:15:01 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangyida.github.io/posts/hineus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Re-direct to the full &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/pdf/2506.23854&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PAPER&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/LiAutoAD&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CODE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;abstrarct&#34;&gt;Abstrarct&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neural surface reconstruction faces persistent challenges in reconciling geometric fidelity with photometric consistency under complex scene conditions. We present HiNeuS, a unified framework that holistically addresses three core limitations in existing approaches: multi-view radiance inconsistency, missing keypoints in textureless regions, and structural degradation from over-enforced Eikonal constraints during joint optimization. To resolve these issues through a unified pipeline, we introduce: 1) Differential visibility verification through SDF-guided ray tracing, resolving reflection ambiguities via continuous occlusion modeling; 2) Planar-conformal regularization via ray-aligned geometry patches that enforce local surface coherence while preserving sharp edges through adaptive appearance weighting; and 3) Physically-grounded Eikonal relaxation that dynamically modulates geometric constraints based on local radiance gradients, enabling detail preservation without sacrificing global regularity. Unlike prior methods that handle these aspects through sequential optimizations or isolated modules, our approach achieves cohesive integration where appearance-geometry constraints evolve synergistically throughout training. Comprehensive evaluations across synthetic and real-world datasets demonstrate state-of-the-art performance, including a 21.4% reduction in Chamfer distance over reflection-aware baselines and 2.32 dB PSNR improvement against neural rendering counterparts. Qualitative analyses reveal superior capability in recovering specular instruments, urban layouts with centimeter-scale infrastructure, and low-textured surfaces without local patch collapse. The method&amp;rsquo;s generalizability is further validated through successful application to inverse rendering tasks, including material decomposition and view-consistent relighting.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-style Street Simulator with Spatial and Temporal Consistency</title>
      <link>https://wangyida.github.io/posts/styledstreets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 01:15:01 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangyida.github.io/posts/styledstreets/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Re-direct to the full &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.21104&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PAPER&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;abstrarct&#34;&gt;Abstrarct&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Urban scene reconstruction demands modeling static infrastructure and dynamic elements while maintaining consistency across diverse environmental conditions. We present &lt;strong&gt;StyledStreets&lt;/strong&gt;, a multi-style street synthesis framework that achieves instruction-driven scene editing with ensured spatial-temporal coherence. Building on 3D Gaussian Splatting, we enhance street scene modeling through novel pose-aware optimization and multi-view training, enabling photorealistic environmental style transfer across seasonal variations, weather conditions, and multi-camera configurations. Our approach introduces three key innovations: (1) a hybrid geometry-appearance embedding architecture that disentangles persistent scene structure from transient stylistic attributes; (2) an uncertainty-aware rendering pipeline mitigating supervision noise from diffusion-based priors; and (3) a unified parametric model enforcing geometric consistency through regularized gradient updates.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Street View Synthesis with Controllable Video Diffusion Models</title>
      <link>https://wangyida.github.io/posts/streetcrafter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 10:15:01 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangyida.github.io/posts/streetcrafter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Re-direct to the full &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.13188&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PAPER&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zju3dv/street_crafter&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CODE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;abstrarct&#34;&gt;Abstrarct&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This paper aims to tackle the problem of photorealistic view synthesis from vehicle sensors data. Recent advancements in neural scene representation have achieved notable success in rendering high-quality autonomous driving scenes, but the performance significantly degrades as the viewpoint deviates from the training trajectory. To mitigate this problem, we introduce &lt;strong&gt;StreetCrafter&lt;/strong&gt;, a novel controllable video diffusion model that utilizes LiDAR point cloud renderings as pixel-level conditions, which fully exploits the generative prior for novel view synthesis, while preserving precise camera control. Moreover, the utilization of pixel-level LiDAR condition allows us to make accurate pixel-level edits to target scenes. In addition, the generative prior of StreetCrafter can be effectively incorporated into dynamic scene representations to achieve real-time rendering. Experiments on Waymo Open and PandaSet datasets demonstrate that our model enables flexible control over viewpoint changes, enlarging the view synthesis regions for satisfying rendering, which outperforms existing methods.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crafting World Models for Driving Scene Reconstruction via Online Restoration</title>
      <link>https://wangyida.github.io/posts/recondreamer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 10:00:01 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangyida.github.io/posts/recondreamer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Re-direct to the full &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.19548&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PAPER&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://recondreamer.github.io/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PROJECT PAGE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/GigaAI-research/ReconDreamer&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CODE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;abstrarct&#34;&gt;Abstrarct&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Closed-loop simulation is crucial for end-to-end autonomous driving. Existing sensor simulation methods (&lt;em&gt;e.g.&lt;/em&gt;, NeRF and 3DGS) reconstruct driving scenes based on conditions that closely mirror training data distributions. However, these methods struggle with rendering novel trajectories, such as lane changes. Recent works have demonstrated that integrating world model knowledge alleviates these issues. Despite their efficiency, these approaches still encounter difficulties in the accurate representation of more complex maneuvers, with multi-lane shifts being a notable example. Therefore, we introduce &lt;strong&gt;ReconDreamer&lt;/strong&gt;, which enhances driving scene reconstruction through incremental integration of world model knowledge. Specifically, DriveRestorer is proposed to mitigate artifacts via online restoration. This is complemented by a progressive data update strategy designed to ensure high-quality rendering for more complex maneuvers. To the best of our knowledge, ReconDreamer is the first method to effectively render in large maneuvers. Experimental results demonstrate that ReconDreamer outperforms Street Gaussians in the NTA-IoU, NTL-IoU, and FID, with relative improvements by 24.87%, 6.72%, and 29.97%. Furthermore,ReconDreamer surpasses DriveDreamer4D with PVG during large maneuver rendering, as verified by a relative improvement of 195.87% in the NTA-IoU metric and a comprehensive user study.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World Models Are Effective Data Machines for 4D Driving Scene Representation</title>
      <link>https://wangyida.github.io/posts/drivedreamer4d/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 10:00:01 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangyida.github.io/posts/drivedreamer4d/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Re-direct to the full &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.13571&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PAPER&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://drivedreamer4d.github.io/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PROJECT PAGE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/GigaAI-research/DriveDreamer4D&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CODE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;abstrarct&#34;&gt;Abstrarct&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Closed-loop simulation is essential for advancing end-to-end autonomous driving systems. Contemporary sensor simulation methods, such as NeRF and 3DGS, rely predominantly on conditions closely aligned with training data distributions, which are largely confined to forward-driving scenarios. Consequently, these methods face limitations when rendering complex maneuvers (e.g., lane change, acceleration, deceleration). Recent advancements in autonomous-driving world models have demonstrated the potential to generate diverse driving videos. However, these approaches remain constrained to 2D video generation, inherently lacking the spatiotemporal coherence required to capture intricacies of dynamic driving environments. In this paper, we introduce DriveDreamer4D, which enhances 4D driving scene representation leveraging world model priors. Specifically, we utilize the world model as a data machine to synthesize novel trajectory videos, where structured conditions are explicitly leveraged to control the spatial-temporal consistency of traffic elements. Besides, the cousin data training strategy is proposed to facilitate merging real and synthetic data for optimizing 4DGS. To our knowledge, DriveDreamer4D is the first to utilize video generation models for improving 4D reconstruction in driving scenarios. Experimental results reveal that DriveDreamer4D significantly enhances generation quality under novel trajectory views, achieving a relative improvement in FID by 32.1%, 46.4%, and 16.3% compared to PVG, S3Gaussian, and Deformable-GS. Moreover, DriveDreamer4D markedly enhances the spatiotemporal coherence of driving agents, which is verified by a comprehensive user study and the relative increases of 22.6%, 43.5%, and 15.6% in the NTA-IoU metric.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ray-adaptive Neural Surface Reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://wangyida.github.io/posts/raneus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 10:15:01 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangyida.github.io/posts/raneus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Re-direct to the full &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/pdf/2406.09801&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PAPER&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wangyida/ra-neus&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CODE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; |&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our objective is to leverage a differentiable radiance field &lt;em&gt;e.g.&lt;/em&gt; NeRF to reconstruct detailed 3D surfaces in addition to producing the standard novel view renderings.
RaNeuS adaptively adjusts the regularization on the signed distance field so that unsatisfying rendering rays won&amp;rsquo;t enforce strong Eikonal regularization which is ineffective, and allow the gradients from regions with well-learned radiance to effectively back-propagated to the SDF.  Consequently, balancing the two objectives in order to generate accurate and detailed surfaces.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rendering, Animating and Meshing Actors with NeRF</title>
      <link>https://wangyida.github.io/posts/neuralactor/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 10:15:01 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangyida.github.io/posts/neuralactor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Re-direct to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wangyida/neural-actor&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CODE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; |&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A library for rendering neural actors, and benchmarking dynamic NeRF&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://wangyida.github.io/posts/neuralactor/images/na1.gif&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://wangyida.github.io/posts/neuralactor/images/na2.gif&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://wangyida.github.io/posts/neuralactor/images/na3.gif&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://wangyida.github.io/posts/neuralactor/images/na4.gif&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;Cite&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you find this work useful in your research, please cite:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;@misc&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;rama2023wang,
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Author &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;Yida Wang&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;,
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Year &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;2023&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;,
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Note &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;https://github.com/wangyida/neural-actor&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;,
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Title &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;Rendering, Animating and Meshing Actors with NeRF&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-supervised Latent Space Optimization with Nebula Variational Coding</title>
      <link>https://wangyida.github.io/posts/nebula/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 10:15:01 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangyida.github.io/posts/nebula/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Re-direct to the full &lt;a href=&#34;https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/9740011/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PAPER&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wangyida/nebula-anchors&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CODE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;abstrarct&#34;&gt;Abstrarct&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deep learning approaches process data in a layer-by-layer way with intermediate (or latent) features. We aim at designing a general solution to optimize the latent manifolds to improve the performance on classification, segmentation, completion and/or reconstruction through probabilistic models. This paper proposes a variational inference model which leads to a clustered embedding. We introduce additional variables in the latent space, called &lt;em&gt;nebula anchors&lt;/em&gt;, that guide the latent variables to form clusters during training. To prevent the anchors from clustering among themselves, we employ the variational constraint that enforces the latent features within an anchor to form a Gaussian distribution, resulting in a generative model we refer as Nebula Variational Coding (NVC). Since each latent feature can be labeled with the closest anchor, we also propose to apply metric learning in a self-supervised way to make the separation between clusters more explicit. As a consequence, the latent variables of our variational coder form clusters which adapt to the generated semantic of the training data, &lt;em&gt;e.g&lt;/em&gt;. the categorical labels of each sample. We demonstrate experimentally that it can be used within different architectures designed to solve different problems including text sequence, images, 3D point clouds and volumetric data, validating the advantage of our proposed method.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning Local Displacements for Point Cloud Completion</title>
      <link>https://wangyida.github.io/posts/lld/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 10:15:01 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangyida.github.io/posts/lld/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Re-direct to the full &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/pdf/2203.16600v1.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PAPER&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wangyida/disp3d&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CODE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/-rSLpHYO78M?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;abstrarct&#34;&gt;Abstrarct&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;th style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;Completing a car&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;th style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;teaser&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://wangyida.github.io/posts/lld/images/CVPR_teaser.png#center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;From the input partial scan to our object completion, we visualize the amount of detail in our reconstruction.&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We propose a novel approach aimed at object and semantic scene completion from a partial scan represented as a 3D point cloud.
Our architecture relies on three novel layers that are used successively within an encoder-decoder structure and specifically developed for the task at hand.
The first one carries out feature extraction by matching the point features to a set of pre-trained local descriptors.
Then, to avoid losing individual descriptors as part of standard operations such as max-pooling, we propose an alternative neighbor-pooling operation that relies on adopting the feature vectors with the highest activations. Finally, up-sampling in the decoder modifies our feature extraction in order to increase the output dimension.
While this model is already able to achieve competitive results with the state of the art, we further propose a way to increase the versatility of our approach to process point clouds. To this aim, we introduce a second model that assembles our layers within a transformer architecture.
We evaluate both architectures on object and indoor scene completion tasks, achieving state-of-the-art performance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Encoder-Decoder Network for Point Cloud Completion</title>
      <link>https://wangyida.github.io/posts/softpoolplus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 10:15:01 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangyida.github.io/posts/softpoolplus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Re-direct to the full &lt;a href=&#34;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s11263-022-01588-7&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PAPER&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CODE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;abstrarct&#34;&gt;Abstrarct&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We propose a novel convolutional operator for the task of point cloud completion. One striking characteristic of our approach is that, conversely to related work it does not require any max-pooling or voxelization operation. Instead, the proposed operator used to learn the point cloud embedding in the encoder extracts permutation-invariant features from the point cloud via a &lt;strong&gt;soft-pooling&lt;/strong&gt; of feature activations, which are able to preserve fine-grained geometric details. These features are then passed on to a decoder architecture. Due to the compression in the encoder, a typical limitation of this type of architectures is that they tend to lose parts of the input shape structure. We propose to overcome this limitation by using skip connections specifically devised for point clouds, where links between corresponding layers in the encoder and the decoder are established. As part of these connections, we introduce a transformation matrix that projects the features from the encoder to the decoder and vice-versa. The quantitative and qualitative results on the task of object completion from partial scans on the ShapeNet dataset show that our approach achieves state-of-the-art performance in shape completion both at low and high resolutions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shape Descriptor for Point Cloud Completion and Classification</title>
      <link>https://wangyida.github.io/posts/softpoolnet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 10:15:01 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangyida.github.io/posts/softpoolnet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Re-direct to the full &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ecva.net/papers/eccv_2020/papers_ECCV/papers/123480069.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PAPER&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wangyida/softpool&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CODE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/zw4NlyxWlBg?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;abstrarct&#34;&gt;Abstrarct&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Point clouds are often the default choice for many applications as they exhibit more flexibility and efficiency than volumetric data. Nevertheless, their unorganized nature &amp;ndash; points are stored in an unordered way &amp;ndash; makes them less suited to be processed by deep learning pipelines. In this paper, we propose a method for 3D object completion and classification based on point clouds. We introduce a new way of organizing the extracted features based on their activations, which we name soft pooling. For the decoder stage, we propose regional convolutions, a novel operator aimed at maximizing the global activation entropy. Furthermore, inspired by the local refining procedure in Point Completion Network (PCN), we also propose a patch-deforming operation to simulate deconvolutional operations for point clouds. This paper proves that our regional activation can be incorporated in many point cloud architectures like AtlasNet and PCN, leading to better performance for geometric completion. We evaluate our approach on different 3D tasks such as object completion and classification, achieving state-of-the-art accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-Branch Volumetric Semantic Completion From a Single Depth Image</title>
      <link>https://wangyida.github.io/posts/forknet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 10:15:01 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangyida.github.io/posts/forknet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Re-direct to the full &lt;a href=&#34;https://openaccess.thecvf.com/content_ICCV_2019/papers/Wang_ForkNet_Multi-Branch_Volumetric_Semantic_Completion_From_a_Single_Depth_Image_ICCV_2019_paper.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PAPER&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wangyida/forknet&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CODE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/1WZ16bGff1o?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;abstrarct&#34;&gt;Abstrarct&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;th style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;Scene completion&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;th style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;Object completion&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;direct&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://wangyida.github.io/posts/forknet/images/ForkNet_nyu.gif#center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;transformer&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://wangyida.github.io/posts/forknet/images/ForkNet_shapenet.gif#center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We propose a novel model for 3D semantic completion from a single depth image, based on a single encoder and three separate generators used to reconstruct different geometric and semantic representations of the original and completed scene, all sharing the same latent space. To transfer information between the geometric and semantic branches of the network, we introduce paths between them concatenating features at corresponding network layers.  Motivated by the limited amount of training samples from real scenes, an interesting attribute of our architecture is the capacity to supplement the existing dataset by generating a new training dataset with high quality, realistic scenes that even includes occlusion and real noise. We build the new dataset by sampling the features directly from latent space which generates a pair of partial volumetric surface and completed volumetric semantic surface. Moreover, we utilize multiple discriminators to increase the accuracy and realism of the reconstructions. We demonstrate the benefits of our approach on standard benchmarks for the two most common completion tasks: semantic 3D scene completion and 3D object completion.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Variational Object-aware 3D Hand Pose from a Single RGB Image</title>
      <link>https://wangyida.github.io/posts/iros_19/handjoints/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 10:15:01 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangyida.github.io/posts/iros_19/handjoints/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Re-direct to the full &lt;a href=&#34;https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/8770083&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PAPER&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wangyida/VO-handpose&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CODE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; |&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/tSTQ2NTqB4A?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;abstrarct&#34;&gt;Abstrarct&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We propose an approach to estimate the 3D pose of a human hand while grasping objects from a single RGB image.  Our approach is based on a probabilistic model implemented with deep architectures, which is used for regressing, respectively, the 2D hand joints heat maps and the 3D hand joints coordinates.  We train our networks so to make our approach robust to large object- and self-occlusions, as commonly occurring with the task at hand. Using specialized latent variables, the deep architecture internally infers the category of the grasped object so to enhance the 3D reconstruction, based on the underlying assumption that objects of a similar category, i.e. with similar shape and size, are grasped in a similar way. Moreover, given the scarcity of 3D hand-object manipulation benchmarks with joint annotations, we propose a new annotated synthetic dataset with realistic images, hand masks, joint masks and 3D joints coordinates. Our approach is flexible as it does not require depth information, sensor calibration, data gloves, or finger markers.  We quantitatively evaluate it on synthetic datasets achieving stateof-the-art accuracy, as well as qualitatively on real sequences.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adversarial Semantic Scene Completion from a Single Depth Image</title>
      <link>https://wangyida.github.io/posts/3dv_18/adversarialssc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 10:15:01 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangyida.github.io/posts/3dv_18/adversarialssc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Re-direct to the full &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/pdf/1810.10901.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PAPER&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wangyida/gan-depth-semantic3d&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CODE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; |&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/udvBhkupwXE?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;abstrarct&#34;&gt;Abstrarct&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We propose a method to reconstruct, complete and semantically label a 3D scene from a single input depth image. We improve the accuracy of the regressed semantic 3D maps by a novel architecture based on adversarial learning. In particular, we suggest using multiple adversarial loss terms that not only enforce realistic outputs with respect to the ground truth, but also an effective embedding of the internal features. This is done by correlating the latent features of the encoder working on partial 2.5D data with the latent features extracted from a variational 3D autoencoder trained to reconstruct the complete semantic scene.  In addition, differently from other approaches that operate entirely through 3D convolutions, at test time we retain the original 2.5D structure of the input during downsampling to improve the effectiveness of the internal representation of our model. We test our approach on the main benchmark datasets for semantic scene completion to qualitatively and quantitatively assess the effectiveness of our proposal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generative Model with Coordinate Metric Learning for Object Recognition Based on 3D Models</title>
      <link>https://wangyida.github.io/posts/tip17/metriclearning3d/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 10:15:01 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangyida.github.io/posts/tip17/metriclearning3d/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;abstrarct&#34;&gt;Abstrarct&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Collecting data for deep learning is so tedious which makes it hard to establish a perfect database. In this paper, we propose a generative model trained with synthetic images rendered from 3D models which can reduce the burden on collecting real training data and make the background conditions more sundry. Our architecture is composed of two subnetworks: semantic foreground object reconstruction network based on Bayesian inference and classification network based on multi-triplet cost training for avoiding over-fitting on monotone synthetic object surface and utilizing accurate informations of synthetic images like object poses and lightning conditions which are helpful for recognizing regular photos. Firstly, our generative model with metric learning utilizes additional foreground object channels generated from semantic foreground object reconstruction sub-network for recognizing the original input images.  Multi-triplet cost function based on poses is used for metric learning which makes it possible training an effective categorical classifier purely based on synthetic data. Secondly, we design a coordinate training strategy with the help of adaptive noises applied on inputs of both of the concatenated sub-networks to make them benefit from each other and avoid inharmonious parameter tuning due to different convergence speed of two subnetworks. Our architecture achieves the state of the art accuracy of 50.5% on ShapeNet database with data migration obstacle from synthetic images to real photos. This pipeline makes it applicable to do recognition on real images only based on 3D models.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient deep learning for real object recognition based on 3D models</title>
      <link>https://wangyida.github.io/posts/zigzagnet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 10:15:01 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangyida.github.io/posts/zigzagnet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;abstrarct&#34;&gt;Abstrarct&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Effective utilization on texture-less 3D models for deep learning is significant to recognition on real photos. We eliminate the reliance on massive real training data by modifying convolutional neural network in 3 aspects: synthetic data rendering for training data generation in large quantities, multi-triplet cost function modification for multi-task learning and compact micro architecture design for producing tiny parametric model while overcoming over-fit problem in texture-less models. Network is initiated with multi-triplet cost function establishing sphere-like distribution of descriptors in each category which is helpful for recognition on regular photos according to pose, lighting condition, background and category information of rendered images. Fine-tuning with additional data further meets the aim of classification on special real photos based on initial model. We propose a 6.2 MB compact parametric model called ZigzagNet based on SqueezeNet to improve the performance for recognition by applying moving normalization inside micro architecture and adding channel wise convolutional bypass through macro architecture.  Moving batch normalization is used to get a good performance on both convergence speed and recognition accuracy. Accuracy of our compact parametric model in experiment on ImageNet and PASCAL samples provided by PASCAL3D+ based on simple Nearest Neighbor classifier is close to the result of 240 MB AlexNet trained with real images. Model trained on texture-less models which consumes less time for rendering and collecting outperforms the result of training with more textured models from ShapeNet.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-restraint Object Recognition by Model Based CNN Learning</title>
      <link>https://wangyida.github.io/posts/selfobject/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 10:15:01 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wangyida.github.io/posts/selfobject/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;abstrarct&#34;&gt;Abstrarct&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CNN has shown excellent performance on object recognition based on huge amount of real images. For training with synthetic data rendered from 3D models alone to reduce the workload of collecting real images, we propose a concatenated self-restraint learning structure lead by a triplet and softmax jointed loss function for object recognition. Locally connected auto encoder trained from rendered images with and without background used for object reconstruction against environment variables produces an additional channel automatically concatenated to RGB channels as input of classification network. This structure makes it possible training a softmax classifier directly from CNN based on synthetic data with our rendering strategy. Our structure halves the gap between training based on real photos and 3D model in both PASCAL and ImageNet database compared to GoogleNet.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
